Frederick B. Serger Papers
Frederick B. Serger Papers
1934-1966
Serger, Frederick, 1889-
1 linear ft.
American landscape and still life painter. Collection contains correspondence, writings, exhibition catalogues and clippings.
3173972
Biographical History
Frederick B. Serger (1889-1965) was an American painter known for his floral still lifes and landscapes.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Frederick B. Serger Papers consists of correspondence, writings, exhibition catalogues and clippings. The bulk of the collection is exhibit catalogs.
Arrangement of the Collection
The entire collection is arranged roughly chronologically.
Subject and Genre Headings
Art -- Painters; Serger, Frederick, 1889-; Art, Modern.; Painters -- United States.; Correspondence.; Exhibition catalogs.; Clippings (information artifacts); Artists.; Painters.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Frederick B. Serger, 1967.
Inventory
- Subject files
  - Bielsko, Poland, Women's portraits, Przyjaciol Sztuk Museum, Krakow, Poland, 1934-1935; news clippings, exhibition catalog (Box 1)
  - Salon des Tuileries, Bernheim-Jeune &c, Paris, 1936; news clippings, admission ticket (Box 1)
  - Salon d'Automne, Paris; purchase of painting "Venice" by the city of Paris, 1936-1937; news clippings, admission ticket, criticism (Box 1)
  - Letters from museum directors in Poland, 1936-1939 (Box 1)
  - Patacu Sztuki, Krakow, Poland; Salon in Museum Malarski, Warsaw, Poland, 1936-1938; clippings, exhibition catalog (Box 1)
  - Salon d'Automne, 1938; exhibition catalog (Box 1)
  - Salon des Tuileries, XVIe Catalogue, 1939 (Box 1)
  - Lilienfeld Galleries exhibition, 1943 (Box 1)
  - "New York as Seen by Artists of Many Lands" / Hoffman, Else, 1944 (Box 1)
  - Exhibition, Lilienfeld Galleries, NY; Carnegi Institute, Pittsburgh, 1945; catalog, clippings, correspondence (Box 1)
  - La Tausca exhibition, 1946; catalog (Box 1)
  - Exhibitions, De Yong Museum, San Francisco and Museum of New Mexico, Santa Fe, 1946; correspondence (Box 1)
  - Schonemann Galleries, one man show; Retrospective 1933-1963, 1946; 1963; catalogs, clippings (Box 1)
  - Painting of the Year, 4th annual; Pepsi Cola exhibition, Rochester Memorial Art Gallery, 1947; catalog (Box 1)
  - Exhibit, Lilienfeld Gallery, NY; various group shows in New York, 1946-1951; clippings, catalogs (Box 1)
  - Corcoran Gallery of Art, Washington, DC; Toledo Museum of Art, Toledo, Ohio, 1947; correspondence, catalogs (Box 1)
  - Springfield Art League, Springfield, Massachusetts, 1947-1952; clippings, catalogs, one piece correspondence (Box 1)
  - Connecticut Gallery of Fine Art, Hartford, Connecticut, 1947-1954; catalog, one piece correspondence (Box 2)
  - Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts, Philadelphia; Detroit Institute of Arts, Detroit, Michigan, 1947-1962; catalogs (Box 2)
  - University of Illinois, Contemporary American Painting, 1948; catalog, one piece correspondence (Box 2)
  - State Teachers College, Indiana, PA, Art Dept, group show, 1948-1949; catalogs, one piece correspondence (Box 2)
  - Woodstock, New York, Rudolph Galleries; New Paltz State Teachers College Art Association, 1948-1950; clippings, catalogs (Box 2)
  - Clearwater Art Museum, Clearwater, Florida; Norton Gallery and School of Art, West Palm Beach, Florida, 1947-1951 (Box 2)
  - Jewish Museum, New York; Diamond Jubilee Art Exhibit, Philadelphia, PA, 1948-1950; catalogs, one piece correspondence (Box 2)
  - Van Diemen, Lilienfeld Galleries, New York, 1950; clippings, catalog (Box 2)
  - Art Association of New Orleans; Isaac Delgado Museum of Art, New Orleans, 1948-1949; catalogs, clippings (Box 2)
  - Painters and Sculptors Society of New Jersey; Jersey City Museum, 1947-1951; catalogs, award, one piece correspondence (Box 2)
  - Butler Institute of American Art, Youngstown, Ohio; one man show, 1951-1955; catalogs, critique (Box 2)
  - John Heller Gallery, New York, 1952-1953; catalog, clippings (Box 2)
  - Frederick Anthony Gallery, Beverly Hills, California; Orr's Gallery, San Diego, California, 1964; catalogs (Box 2)
  - Louuisiana Art Commission Galleries; Baton Rouge, Louisiana retrospective show, 1965; catalogs, clippings, correspondence, publicity (Box 2)
  - La Boetie, New York, 1965; catalog, clippings (Box 2)
  - Obituary, 1965 (Box 2)
  - Memorial exhibition, La Boetie, 1966; catalog, clippings (Box 2)
  - Statements about paintings, by Serger, Undated (Box 2)
  - Fan mail, Undated (Box 2)
  - La Boetie Gallery Collection, Undated; `exhibition catalogs, press release (Box 2)